<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>linux - Tag - Ang's Blog</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>linux - Tag - Ang's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://anggao.github.io/tags/linux/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install Arch Linux in virtualbox</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/2020-10-12-install-arch-linux-in-virtualbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://anggao.github.io/2020-10-12-install-arch-linux-in-virtualbox/</guid><description>Pre-installation Acquire an installation image Arch is a “rolling release” distribution, download the .iso file from its offical site.
Create VM Create a vm in virtualbox, make sure enable EFI in the motherboard. We will use use UEFI instead of the older BIOS spec to boot the VM.
Verify the boot mode To verify the boot mode, list the efivars directory:
1 # ls /sys/firmware/efi/efivars If the command shows the directory without error, then the system is booted in UEFI mode.</description></item><item><title>Network 02</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/2018-09-16-network-02/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://anggao.github.io/2018-09-16-network-02/</guid><description>Network Interfaces Network interfaces represent a point of connection between a computer and a network. interfaces can be software or hardware /proc filesystem /proc/net/[tcp|udp|raw] /proc/net/route /proc/net/dev /proc/net/arp /proc/net/snmp /proc/sys/net which concerns various networking topics /proc/sys/net/core/ message_burst, message_cost message_burst defaults to 10 and message_cost defaults to 5. This means the kernel is limited to logging 10 entries every 5 seconds. netdev_max_backlog maximum number of packets allowed to queue on a particular interface.</description></item><item><title>Network 01</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/2018-08-12-network-01/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://anggao.github.io/2018-08-12-network-01/</guid><description>MAC Media access control (MAC) addresses are identifiers uniquely assigned to network interfaces. first 3 octets refer to the Organizationally Unique Identifier (OUI) which can help identify manufacturers IP IP addresses are means of identifying devices connected to a network under Internet Protocol. In IPv4 we can partition a block of addresses into a subnet. The number that comes after the slash (/) is the subnet mask. This represents how many bits are in the network address, the remaining bits identify a host within the network.</description></item><item><title>ssh to virtualbox guest OS</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/2013-04-22-ssh-to-virtualbox-guest-os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://anggao.github.io/2013-04-22-ssh-to-virtualbox-guest-os/</guid><description> sudo apt-get install ssh make sure ssh service is working netstat -tlp
you should see following line:
1 tcp 0 0 *:ssh *:* LISTEN change virtualbox network setting to: Bridged Adapter with vnic0
ifconfig make sure host OS vnic0 address is in the same net with guest OS p2p1</description></item></channel></rss>