<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>golang - Tag - Ang's Blog</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/tags/golang/</link><description>golang - Tag - Ang's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://anggao.github.io/tags/golang/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Golang Note Six</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/2015-08-25-golang-note-six/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://anggao.github.io/2015-08-25-golang-note-six/</guid><description>There are two types of Go programs: executables and libraries. Executable applications are the kinds of programs that we can run directly from the terminal Libraries are collections of code that we package together so that we can use them in other programs Types Numbers Go has several different types to represent numbers. Generally we split numbers into two different kinds: integers and floating-point numbers. Go&amp;rsquo;s integer types are: uint8, uint16, uint32, uint64, int8, int16, int32 and int64.</description></item><item><title>Golang Note Five</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/2015-06-13-golang-note-five/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://anggao.github.io/2015-06-13-golang-note-five/</guid><description>Select The select statement lets a goroutine wait on multiple communication operations. A select blocks until one of its cases can run, then it executes that case. It chooses one at random if multiple are ready. Default Selection The default case in a select is run if no other case is ready. Use a default case to try a send or receive without blocking: 1 2 3 4 5 6 select { case i := &amp;lt;-c: // use i default: // receiving from c would block }</description></item><item><title>Golang Note Four</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/2015-05-06-golang-note-four/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://anggao.github.io/2015-05-06-golang-note-four/</guid><description>Goroutines A goroutine is a lightweight thread managed by the Go runtime. 1 go f(x, y, z) The evaluation of f, x, y, and z happens in the current goroutine and the execution of f happens in the new goroutine. Goroutines run in the same address space, so access to shared memory must be synchronized. The sync package provides useful primitives, although you won&amp;rsquo;t need them much in Go as there are other primitives.</description></item><item><title>Golang Note Three</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/2015-05-05-golang-note-three/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://anggao.github.io/2015-05-05-golang-note-three/</guid><description>Methods Go does not have classes. However, you can define methods on struct types. The method receiver appears in its own argument list between the func keyword and the method name. You can declare a method on any type that is declared in your package, not just struct types. You cannot define a method on a type from another package (including built in types). Methods can be associated with a named type or a pointer to a named type.</description></item><item><title>Golang Note Two</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/2015-04-23-golang-note-two/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://anggao.github.io/2015-04-23-golang-note-two/</guid><description><![CDATA[Flow control statements  Go has only one looping construct, the for loop. For is Go&rsquo;s &ldquo;while&rdquo; Like for, the if statement can start with a short statement to execute before the condition. A case body breaks automatically, unless it ends with a fallthrough statement. A defer statement defers the execution of a function until the surrounding function returns. The deferred call&rsquo;s arguments are evaluated immediately, but the function call is not executed until the surrounding function returns.]]></description></item><item><title>Golang Note One</title><link>http://anggao.github.io/2015-04-20-golang-note-one/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://anggao.github.io/2015-04-20-golang-note-one/</guid><description><![CDATA[Basics  Every Go program is made up of packages. Programs start running in package main. factored import statement.  1 2 3 4  import ( &#34;fmt&#34; &#34;math&#34; )    In Go, a name is exported if it begins with a capital letter. Functions in Golang  1 2 3  func add(x int, y int) int { return x + y }    When two or more consecutive named function parameters share a type, you can omit the type from all but the last.]]></description></item></channel></rss>